http://www.malwarebytes.org/privacy/

Cloud Console
When do we collect your information?
What information do we collect?
How do we collect your information?
Last Updated: October 6, 2020
We believe you have the right to a malware-free existence. We also believe just as strongly that you have the right to privacy and control over your information. This fundamental belief shapes our Privacy Policy.
We will be clear about the data we collect and why. We do not and will not sell your data to third parties. Our primary purpose in collecting your data is to be able to equip you with effective products and services that provide a more agile, dynamic response to new and unknown threats.
This Privacy Policy applies to Malwarebytes websites and products and describes how Malwarebytes collects, uses, shares and secures your personal information. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information.
Please, if you have any questions or suggestions, don't hesitate to contact us at privacy@malwarebytes.com.
Caution: Legalese ahead.
When do we collect your information?
We may collect your information: (1) when you license and use our software ("Software Collection"); (2) when you interact with certain portions of our website, such as our forums, blogs, and support center ("Website Collection"); (3) when you communicate with us by email, chat, or otherwise ("Dialogue Collection"); and (4) when you apply to work for us (“Job Applicant Collection”)
Simply
We collect your information when you use our software, website, or otherwise communicate with us.
What information do we collect?
We may collect both personal information and non-personal information. personal information is information that is either expressly provided by you, such as your name, or information that can be used either alone or in combination with other information to personally identify you, such as your email address, phone number, and user name.
We may collect the following personal information from you: Contact Information (such as name, email address, mailing address, or phone number); Unique Identifiers (such as username and password used for authenticating your Malwarebytes accounts and products) and machine identification number; Information about your business (such as company name, company size, business type) and; Information related to your usage of our products as described in the next section, below.
Our service providers may collect billing information (credit card number and billing address) on our behalf to process orders.
Non-personal information is all information that is not personal information or is information that was personal information but which we modify and/or aggregate with other data in order to make it Non-personal information. As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate, and anonymously generated device identifiers and administer the site.
Simply
There are two types of information we collect: personal and non-personal.
Software Collection – information collected when using our security software
User-Agent String
Each API communication coming from any of our client software identifies itself with a string that includes information about the software itself:
The program and build which is sending the request
The current license state (as identified by the product)
The version of the software as well as any subcomponents (currently, databases) that it uses
Why?
So we can manage your Malwarebytes product and ensure that it is up to date.
GeoIP Data
When we collect data from our client systems, we do not store IP address from which the request originates. However, we do use it to gather geographic information on the system calling in:
A location item indicating the continent, country, city, and approximate latitude/ longitude of the user based on your IP address
The type of connection (dialup/broadband/satellite/mobile)
The ISP through which the connection is made
The organization to which the IP address is licensed, if any
Why?
So our malware intelligence team can track malware and potentially unwanted program ("PUP") outbreaks and patterns.
Functional Data
We collect data that is necessary for the functionality of the software or for our performance of providing the software to you. For example, we may need to collect system processes and behaviors in order to perform system rollback and recovery operations.
Why?
So our products are able to function as intended, including being able to detect and remediate malware and PUPs, and provide rollback and recovery operations.
Client Data
In addition to functional data, we collect client data from each program that describe the client environment (i.e., our software and the computer system it is running on). In this, we collect:
The operating system the program is installed on
The system language in use on that system
The processor architecture (i.e., 32- or 64-bit)
The file system in use (i.e., FAT32)
Information from the Windows Security/Action Center, including security settings and programs installed or in use
Information about other Malwarebytes program settings and how they are configured
Information about how you use our software or services ("Log Data")
Why?
So we can gather performance data around our products and how they operate in relation to different hardware and software environments. By having this data, we can improve our products as well as optimize them for the various system configurations that our users are using.
Machine Identification Data
We identify each system by assigning each system with a Malwarebytes-generated distinct identifier that is created at install time.
Why?
So we are able to get an accurate count of our install base. We are also able to identify changes to an individual system over time, allowing us to recognize trends which are used for improving our products.
License Data
We collect data from products corresponding to the products' applicable license state. These data also use a unique identifier. In this, we collect:
The key or keys used to license the current product
The type of license being used
If it represents a console system, the number of seats being managed by that installation of the console
Endpoint and network domain information
Why?
So we can remind you when your Malwarebytes subscription is about to expire or to determine the correct license type. We may use such license data in conjunction with other software collection to assist you in resolving licensing issues.
Malware and PUP Data
We collect data about the malware and PUPs that are detected by our products. We collect:
The vendor name of the malware or PUP removed
An encrypted description of which database rule was used to remove the malware or PUP in question
Artifacts detected as malware, PUPs, or suspicious files
Information related to detected artifacts
Why?
So our malware intelligence team can track malware and PUP outbreaks and improve the efficacy of Malwarebytes products.
Trial Data
When a client attempts to start a trial, we track it remotely in order to validate that the trial is allowed. For this information we use another unique system identifier. We collect:
The client's request for a trial
The start date and duration of the trial provided
Any attempted conversion/purchase generated by clicking an in-app link, so that it can be correlated with a trial
Why?
So we can update your Malwarebytes products accurately and when they need it.
Exploit Data
In Malwarebytes Anti-Exploit products we collect a complex data object for any exploit process which is blocked by the software. In this data we collect:
Process ID of the exploit process
File path of exploit process
MD5 hash of the exploit payload, if any
Command-line arguments passed to the exploit
A list of URLs potentially associated with the exploit, including redirect jumps if any
Exploit payload files
Exploit file-format (doc, pdf, xls, etc…)
(Potentially) a copy of the exploit executable itself
Why?
So our malware intelligence team can track exploit outbreaks and deepen its understanding of new exploit techniques.
Mobile Application Data
When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the unique device identifier.
We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.
We do not ask for, access or track any location-based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or Services.
We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.
As part of our text message filtering functionality, our Mobile Software also collects text messages from senders who are not in your contacts, and analyzes these text messages to determine whether they are malicious. We only receive the sender information and the body of the message which is analyzed to determine if they contain malicious URLs or come from malicious senders; no information is provided about the recipient. Text messages that are malicious are retained for analysis by our researchers, however, all other text messages are discarded.
Simply
We collect information that allows us to fight against malware and PUPs on your device and contact you if you allow us to send push notifications.
Software Collection – information collected when using our Malwarebytes Privacy software
License Data
As part of installation and activation of your Malwarebytes Privacy application, we:
Collect the key used to license the product; and
Generate a unique identifier.
Why?
So that we can activate your license, validate your account, and assist you in resolving licensing issues.
Software Version
We identify what version of the Malwarebytes Privacy application you are running.
Why?
So that we can provide you with updates to the Malwarebytes Privacy product.
Malwarebytes Privacy’s WireGuard public key
Your Malwarebytes Privacy application generates a cryptographic public/private key pair.
We only receive the public key which is used to validate and establish a VPN connection.
Your public/private key pair is periodically changed for increased security.
Why?
So that your Malwarebytes Privacy application is able to connect to the VPN service as allowed under the applicable device limit associated with your purchase.
The Malwarebytes Privacy application does not collect or retain the following:
Details about the websites or IP addresses browsed on your device;
DNS requests made by you;
Bandwidth usage on your device;
Network details of your device, including IP address;
Telemetry data from the Malwarebytes Privacy application, including telemetry on functionality and on system environment; OR
Local Malwarebytes Privacy application logs. These logs are only available on your device and can be helpful for diagnostic purposes if you experience connectivity issues. If you have an issue with the application you can choose to submit a copy of the log to our support team, but we do not automatically receive it.
Website and Dialogue Collection
As part of our Website Collection and Dialogue Collection we collect and we ask you to provide information about yourself including but not limited to:
Contact details, including but not limited to your name, address, e-mail address;
User ID and password, if you establish a Malwarebytes account;
Chat and video conference information, you provide when interacting with our teams;
Information about your device, including browser type and web traffic information
Why?
Providing your data is optional, but it may be necessary for certain services, accessing content, such as whitepapers and webinars, or to receive customer support services. In such cases, if you do not provide your information, we may not be able to provide you with the requested services.
Job Applicant Collection
When you apply for a position at Malwarebytes, we ask you to provide information about yourself including, but not limited to:
Contact details, including but not limited to your name, address, e-mail address;
Your past education and job history, and other customary details you include on your resume or curriculum vitae; and
Voluntary EEO or similar data required to comply with applicable laws, including equal Employment Opportunity record keeping, reporting, and other legal requirements.
Simply
We collect your information when you give it to us as part of a job application.
How do we collect your information?
Directly
Some information you (or someone acting on your behalf) provide to us directly. For example, when you post comments, ask questions in our blog, fill out a user profile, apply for a job, or voluntarily decide to grant us remote access to provide you with technical support. Also, we may collect and store all posted forum and blog information and user profiles and make them available for public viewing.
Simply
We collect your information when you give it to us or post in forums or blogs.
Cookies
Malwarebytes and its service providers collect information through "cookies" and other similar tracking technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Cookies are text files saved by your browser when you log into our software or services. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to identify that you have logged in, to tell us how and when you interact with our software or services, and to check aggregate usage and web traffic. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted when you log off and close your browser. If you prefer, you can always change your browser options to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting cookies. However, if you do not accept cookies you may not be able to access the entirety of our software and services.
Simply
We also collect your information using "cookies" and other similar tracking technologies when you visit our website. You can prevent this method of information collection if you like.
You may manage your Cookie Settings for our website here. We have classified our cookies into four different categories which we have described below. Within the Cookie Settings, you may choose not to allow certain categories of cookies.
However, you should know that blocking some types of cookies may impact your experience on the site and the services we are able to offer.
Click here to manage your cookie and privacy preferences.
Stricly Necessary Cookies
These cookies are necessary for our website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for our services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms.
Simply
By the nature of the category name, these cookies are necessary for us to make our website function.
Performance Cookies
These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources, so we can measure and improve the performance of our website. They help us know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around our website. These cookies collect this information in an aggregated manner, which keeps you anonymous.
Simply
These cookies collect anonymized information that help us improve our website, and as a result, enhances your browsing experience.
Functional Cookies
These cookies allow the provision of enhance functionality and personalization, such as remembering language preferences and remembering where you paused a video to allow you to resume playing where you left off.
Simply
These cookies help us personalize our website for you by remembering your preferences and settings.
Targeting Cookies
These cookies are set through our website by our marketing partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant ads on other websites.
Simply
These cookies help deliver content to you that is tailored to your interests based on information from your visit.
Account Registration
If you create an account with us through a third party like Facebook or Twitter ("SNS Accounts") you may have to provide us with your user name or user ID so that we can authenticate your identity.
Simply
We collect your information when you create an account.
Software Functionality
Our software collects information about your use of the software as well as transfers of information between your computers that run the software and our servers. This is necessary to ensure our software is operating correctly and to confirm the status of your license of our software.
Simply
We collect information about your Malwarebytes license.
From Third Parties
We receive information about you from distributors and resellers who sell our products and services to you, as well as payment processors who process payments you make for purchasing our products and services.
Simply
We collect information about your Malwarebytes purchases where you make them through third-parties.
How do we use personal information
We use personal information for the following business purposes: providing you with information, products or services; providing support to you and responding to your requests; correspondence with you about our products, services, events, or news; performing and enforcing any contract(s) between yourself and Malwarebytes, including billing and collections;
to improve our products and services, including malware research, as well as our websites and present content to you; as described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise allowed by applicable law.
We will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.
Other than with respect to the exceptions below, we do not share personal information with third parties
Simply
We use your information for providing you with our services.
In certain situations, described below, we may share your personal information with a third party.
Exceptions
Website Analytics
Our servers automatically record Log Data information about how a user interacts with our software and services on our websites, including but not limited to our public website and our web-based management consoles. Log Data may include a user's Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, operating system, web page that the user was visiting before accessing our server, search terms, and the pages or features of our software or services accessed by the user and the time spent there. Google Analytics provides us with the analysis of such data. Google's privacy policy is available at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy.
Simply
Exception #1: We receive your website interaction information from Google for analytical purposes.
Service Providers
We may engage service providers to administer and provide our services. We may provide personal information to such service providers only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders and delivering updates, payment processing, providing customer service, sending marketing communications, conducting research and analysis, and providing cloud computing infrastructure. We require such service providers to agree not to disclose your personal information or use your personal information for any other purpose.
For our cloud-based Software, we utilize Amazon Web Services for our infrastructure.
With such infrastructure, you are able to benefit from Amazon Web Services Cloud Compliance security and privacy measures, including but not limited to ISO and SOC certifications. For more information on Amazon Web Services Cloud Compliance please visit https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/.
Simply
Exception #2: If we give your information to a service provider company, they won't use your information outside of our business relationship.
Business Transactions
Information that we collect from users, including personal information, is considered a business asset. Accordingly, if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, or if we are acquired, e.g., as a result of a transaction such as a merger, acquisition, or asset sale, your personal information may be disclosed or transferred to the third-party acquirer in connection with the transaction. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choice you may have regarding your personal information.
Simply
Exception #3: If someone buys us or we go bankrupt, your information may be transferred to someone else.
Governmental; Law Enforcement
We may disclose personal information to government agencies, law enforcement officials, and private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary: (1) to satisfy or comply with any applicable law, regulation or legal process; (2) to respond to lawful requests, including subpoenas, warrants or court orders; (3) to protect our property, rights and safety and the rights, property and safety of third parties or the public in general; and (4) to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.
In certain situations, Malwarebytes may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
Simply
Exception #4: If the government asks for your information, we may comply.
Consent
We may share your personal information with third-party sites or platforms, such as social networking sites, but only if you have expressly requested that we do so.
Similarly, by posting profile, content, or other information, including personal information to a forum or blog, you indicate your consent to its public use. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. We will list you in our publicly accessible member directory on the forum website.
We also display testimonials of satisfied customers on our websites in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@malwarebytes.com.
Simply
Exception #5: If you post your information in one of our forums or on the blog, well, that's public.
Other Privacy Considerations
The Legal Bases for Using Personal Information
The General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 ("GDPR") effective May 25, 2018. The GDPR requires that a valid legal basis be used to process personal data. In certain countries, there are different legal bases that we rely on to use your personal information, namely:
Performance of a contract
The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the agreement you have with us. For example, to complete your purchase of your product, to register and maintain your account and to make sure that your product performs its functions in a secure way or to respond to your requests.
Legitimate interests
We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests. For example, we rely on our legitimate interest to analyze and improve our products and the content on our websites, to send you notifications about software updates or information about products or to use your personal information for administrative, fraud detection or legal purposes.
Legal obligation
We may use your personal information to comply with legal requirements, as further described in Exception 4, above.
Consent
We may at times, request your consent to conduct certain actions with your personal information. When requesting your consent, we are transparent in ensuring you know what you are consenting to.
Simply
These are the legal bases we use for processing data subject to the GDPR.
California Residents
If you are California resident, you can find more information about your rights on our California Residents Privacy Notice Supplement.
Simply
California residents can learn more about their rights on our California Residents Privacy Notice Supplement.
Choice
We partner with a third-party service provider to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party service provider may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click here [or if located in the European Union click here]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.
You may sign-up to receive email or newsletter or other communications from us. By interacting with us, such as attending a webinar, attending our sponsored events or downloading content from our website, you may be added to our mailing list. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the "Unsubscribe" link found in emails we send to you or at your member profile on our website or by contacting us at privacy@malwarebytes.com.
You may have the right to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information as required by the Privacy Shield Frameworks principles, such as whether your personal information is disclosed to a third party or used for purposes materially different from the purpose for which the personal information was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. If you wish to limit the use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the Privacy Shield Frameworks principles, please contact us
using our online request form.
Usage and Threat Statistics
You may opt out of usage and threat statistics collection in certain Malwarebytes products within the settings. Threat statistics collection includes detection samples and their corresponding statistics. Usage statistics includes behavior usage tracking. Do it in just a couple of clicks. To opt out please follow the instructions below.
Using Malwarebytes for Home on Windows:
From the Navigation menu select Settings
Scroll down to "Usage and Threat Statistics"
Untick the box that reads "Anonymously help fight malware by providing usage and threat statistics"
Usage and threat statistics collection will be disabled
Using Malwarebytes for Android
From the Navigation menu select Settings
Scroll down to the General section
Untick the box that reads "Help us Anonymously"
Usage and threat statistics collection will be disabled
Using Malwarebytes for Mac:
Open Malwarebytes and click Settings
Uncheck "Help fight malware by providing usage and threat statistics"
Usage and threat statistics collection will be disabled
Using Malwarebytes for iOS:
Open Malwarebytes and tap Settings
Turn off "Share anonymous telemetry"
Whitelisted phone number and URL collection will be disabled
You may change your preferences at any time following the same steps.
Simply
We want to give you control to manage your data.
Security
We take commercially reasonable measures to protect personal information from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. However, no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure. Accordingly, we can't guarantee the absolute security of your personal information.
Simply
We do what we reasonably can to protect your information.
Retention
We will retain your personal information as needed to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our business requirements, legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect our assets, and enforce our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different products or services, actual retention periods can vary significantly.
Simply
Our retention periods differ for each type of personal information, but we only retain such information to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected.
Links
Our website may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or services and we are not responsible for the content, privacy, or security practices and policies of those websites or services.
Simply
Our privacy policy doesn't apply when you visit sites we link to.
Update or Delete your personal information
Upon request, Malwarebytes will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access or modify the personal information associated with your use of our services at any time by updating your "My Account" information by navigating to my.malwarebytes.com, signing into your account and updated your personal information. Similarly, you may delete your My Account itself by logging into my.malwarebytes.com. Alternatively, you may submit a data subject access request to access, modify, or delete (subject to applicable law) the personal information associated with your use of our services. If you want us to delete your personal information, your forum account, or your support account, please contact us at privacy@malwarebytes.com with your request. We will respond to your requests within a reasonable timeframe. We will delete your information as soon as possible; however, some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law. We may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.
For our Partnerbytes Platform only:
Malwarebytes acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information.
Malwarebytes has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the Malwarebytes' Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.
In certain circumstances we may be required by law to retain your personal information or may need to retain your personal information in order to continue providing a service.
Simply
Subject to applicable laws, we'll delete or modify your information if you ask.
International
Your personal information may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide your personal information to us, we may transfer your personal information to the United States and process it there.
Malwarebytes participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (collectively, "Privacy Shield Frameworks").
Malwarebytes is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Frameworks, to the Frameworks' applicable Principles.
To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield List.
Malwarebytes is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Malwarebytes complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Malwarebytes is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Malwarebytes may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
Simply
If you're not in the U.S., we may transfer your information to the U.S. We participate in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.
Children
Our services are not directed to children under eighteen, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under thirteen. If we learn that we have collected personal information of a child under thirteen we will delete such information from our files as soon as possible, provided, however, that some information may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law.
Simply
We don't knowingly collect information on children, and delete it if we inadvertently do collect it.
Revisions
We may modify and revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you of such changes by posting them on our website or by sending you an email or other notification prior to the change becoming effective.
Simply
We'll let you know if we revise our privacy policy. If we make a material change, we will let you know before the change takes place.
Questions? Please contact us @ 3979 Freedom Circle, 12th Floor, Santa Clara, CA 95054 or via email at privacy@malwarebytes.com if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy
Cybersecurity info you can't do without
Want to stay informed on the latest news in cybersecurity? Sign up for our newsletter and learn how to
protect your computer from threats.
Select your language
Cybersecurity basics
Your intro to everything relating to cyberthreats, and how to stop them.
What is EDR?
What is endpoint protection?
Pharming
Ryuk ransomware
Trickbot
